



Denis Aleksandrov

Date of birth: 13 Oct 1980

Nationality: Macedonian/citizen of the Republic of North Macedonia | **Phone number:**

(+389) 77975812 (Mobile) | Email address: denis.v.aleksandrov@gmail.com | Website:

https://github.com/denal05 | Website: https://denal05.github.io/ | Website:

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~0167bf0c63f8a21b6e | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/denal05 | **Skype:** denal05 |

WhatsApp Messenger: +38977975812 | Viber: +38977975812 |

Address: Krchin 3/11, 1000, Skopje, North Macedonia (Home)

ABOUT ME

An experienced, proactive, and organised cross-domain software engineering professional who gained broad technical knowledge through many trials, including programming Magento 2 e-commerce shops, Linux+Apache+MySQL+PHP web apps, iOS mobile apps, Qt desktop apps, Java enterprise apps, and embedded systems firmware. Twenty years of experience in IT. Professional interpersonal communication skills. Solid understanding of entrepreneurship, project management, regulatory compliance, quality assurance, technical writing, operations, human resources, finance, sales, marketing, etc. Had a pivotal role in creating two FDA-certified medical devices. Myers-Briggs Type Indicator (MBTI): Introversion, Sensing, Thinking, Judgment (ISTJ) personality type. Top 5 strengths per Gallup StrenghtsFinder: Learner, Responsibility, Connectedness, Relator, and Discipline.

Mission: TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE, TO GROW IN CHARACTER, AND TO SEIZE THE DAY!

DIGITAL SKILLS

Magento

Magento | Malware Detection and Removal | Docker | PHP | MySQL | JavaScript | jQuery | KnockOut.js | Magento Repositories | Magento Collections | Import & Export | Templates | Admin Panel Config Parameters | Mailchimp Integration | Custom Logs | Layout | Google Analytics Integration | Store Pickup Integration | Cronjob Management | OpenGraph Integration | Tax Configuration | Algolia Integration | Categories | Firebase Realtime Database Integration | Firebase Authentication Integration | Stock Management | Shipping Module | Reward Points Integration | CashOnDelivery Payment Method | Preorder Integration | Events and Observers | SMTP Integration | Email Template Configuration | Plugins | Giftcard Integration | Facebook Authentication Integration | Localization (i18n) | REST APIs | Postman | Payment Gateway Integration | Payment Gateways | XML | JSON | Atlassian (Bitbucket, Confluence, Jira) | Git | AWS | E-commerce | PhpStorm

iOS

iOS | Swift | SwiftUI | Objective-C | Xcode | Bluetooth Low Energy | Core Location | Core Data | Core Bluetooth | Core ML | Create ML | SQLite | Firebase | Realm DB

Embedded Systems

ARM | IAR Embedded Workbench | IoT | Qt | Arduino | Embedded Systems | C | C++

Web Development

Software Engineering | TypeScript | Bootstrap | Node.js | Express.js | Perl | CRUD | HTML | Linux | CSS | PostgreSQL | SQL | Typescript | Java | Tomcat | Apache | Nginx

Project Management

Project Management | Regulatory Compliance | Procurement

Quality Assurance

Manual Testing | Regression Testing | Writing Test Cases

WORK EXPERIENCE

6 NOV 2023 - 31 AUG 2024 (remote), Serbia

MAGENTO 2 DEVELOPER SYNCIT GROUP DOO

Upgraded Magento websites of existing production environments from 2.3 and 2.4 to 2.6 and 2.7. Created various Docker environments for Magento 2. Detected and removed malware. Customized the Magento 2 checkout. Wrote custom modules.

1 FEB 2023 - 16 JUN 2023 (remote), Spain

MAGENTO 2 DEVELOPER NTT DATA SPAIN FOR CLIENT ORANGE BELGIUM

Backend Magento 2 developer coding modules according to user stories and providing defect fixes in staging and production environments. Worked extensively on "bulk order status update" functionality and Algolia integration. Also worked on the "onepage" checkout customization.

1 JUN 2021 – 1 DEC 2022 (remote), United Kingdom

MAGENTO 2 TECH SUPPORT ENGINEER ON TAP GROUP

I provided first-tier technical support to e-commerce clients via the help desk and live chat, covering products and services, triaging issues, and providing partial or full solutions. The products included extensions for Magento 2, OpenCart, PrestaShop, and WooCommerce. The services included custom B2B and B2C Magento 2 module development and bi-weekly deployment of modules from scratch, custom modification of 3rd-party modules, and integration of 3rd-party modules. The software development process used an agile software development methodology with bi-weekly sprints.

2 DEC 2018 - 15 APR 2021 Skopje, North Macedonia

PROJECT LEAD & MAGENTO 2 DEVELOPER CODEWELL UNLIMITED DOO

Responsible for project management using Scrumban methodology.

Mostly backend and some frontend development for the e-commerce platform Magento 2, running on Amazon Web Services. For more information regarding the projects I worked on, please see https://denal05.github.io

17 MAR 2011 – 1 OCT 2018 Skopje, North Macedonia

PROJECT MANAGER INFORM DOO

Responsible for project management, regulatory compliance, quality assurance, technical writing, software development, system administration, operations, procurement, human resources and corporate social responsibility. Major clients between 2011 and 2018 have been: IntriCon, Gauge Telematics and The SnapBar.

22 FEB 2009 – 1 MAR 2011 Skopje, North Macedonia

JUNIOR DEVELOPER | JUNIOR TESTER | CONFIGURATION MANAGER SEAVUS

Studied the ARM architecture. Utilised working procedures and protocols fundamental to source code development within Seavus. Performed testing on software as part of Quality Assurance. Responsible for Configuration Management of software as part of Quality Assurance.

30 SEP 2007 - 30 APR 2008 Hayward, CA, United States

COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHER MOREAU CATHOLIC HIGH SCHOOL

Instructed students on three subjects: Computer Essentials with Microsoft Office, Introduction to Computer Science using Java, and Advanced Placement Computer Science for the College Board AP CS A exam (subset of J2SE 1.5.0). Clarified fundamental Computer Science concepts. Encouraged discipline, diligence, and design.

31 MAY 2007 - 31 OCT 2007 Hayward, CA, United States

APPLICATION ENGINEER MOVELL SOFTWARE, INC.

Integrated weekly source code releases of Movell's real-time remote diagnostic software engine I-DEAL onto a development board running embedded Linux using the GNU ARM toolchain. Demonstrated the diagnostic software to potential customers.

31 JAN 2007 - 30 APR 2007 Hayward, CA, United States

ENTRY LEVEL JAVA DEVELOPER DIVVIO

Coordinated release builds, extended functionality of media player integration, and implemented new features of the flagship product: a Web2.0 application that aggregates video and audio content on the Internet.

30 APR 2005 - 30 DEC 2005

IT SPECIALIST NORMAN CHRYSLER JEEP DODGE

Single-handedly maintained and expanded the entire IT infrastructure (including desktops, servers, databases, and networking equipment) of a major automobile dealership with satellite offices. Made decisions in purchasing and coordinating with technology goods and services. Involved with all aspects of security.

30 APR 2000 - 31 OCT 2003 Edmond, OK, United States

MICROLAB COORDINATOR / MICROCOMPUTER LAB TECHNICIAN (HELP DESK) OFFICE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY AT THE UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL OKLAHOMA

Assisted Technology Support with work orders, including PC rebuilds/installation/removal/upgrades, and basic and intermediate troubleshooting. Helped with the disposition of surplus computer equipment, including destroying data, salvaging parts, and rebuilding PCs. Checked IT computer labs and delivered printer supplies as needed.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

31 MAY 2006 - 30 APR 2008 Fremont, CA, United States

MS, ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING Northwestern Polytechnic University (San Francisco Bay University)

Website https://www.sfbu.edu

31 DEC 1999 - 30 APR 2005 Edmond, OK, United States

BS, COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Central Oklahoma

Website https://www.uco.edu

1 JUL 2024 - CURRENT

CUSTOMIZE THE MAGENTO 2 CHECKOUT M.academy

Website https://m.academy

1 OCT 2023 - 31 OCT 2023

TRANSFORM MAGENTO 2 ADMIN GRIDS & FORMS M.academy

Website https://m.academy

1 SEP 2023 - 30 SEP 2023

MAGENTO 2 CODING KICKSTART M.academy

Website https://m.academy

31 JAN 2020 - CURRENT

IOS 13 & SWIFT 5 - THE COMPLETE IOS APP DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP Udemy

Website udemy.com

30 SEP 2018 - 30 OCT 2018

SWIFT 4 FUNDAMENTALS SoloLearn

Website https://www.sololearn.com/Certificate/1075-8808678/pdf/

30 JUN 2016 - 30 JUL 2016 Skopje, North Macedonia

IOS ADVANCED TRAINING IN OBJECTIVE-C Seavus Education and Development Center

Address 11 Oktomvri 33A, 1000, Skopje, North Macedonia | Website https://www.sedc.mk

31 MAY 2016 - 29 JUN 2016 Skopje, North Macedonia

IOS BASIC TRAINING IN OBJECTIVE-C Seavus Education and Development Center

Address 11 Oktomvri 33A, 1000, Skopje, North Macedonia | Website https://www.sedc.mk

CERTIFIED JAVA PROGRAMMER FOR THE JAVA 2 PLATFORM 1.4 Sun Microsystems

Website oracle.com

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): MACEDONIAN

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
SERBIAN	C2	C2	B2	B2	B2
CROATIAN	C1	C1	A1	A1	A1
BULGARIAN	C1	C1	A2	A2	A1
ALBANIAN	A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: B

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Volunteer Experience

Organization Name: YouVersion Role: Localization Volunteer

Dates volunteered: Jul 2011 - Present

Faithfully serving as a volunteer on the team that localizes the most popular Bible app for iOS, Android, and web into

the Macedonian language. https://www.bible.com/

Organization Name: SEAM (IFES/InterVarsity)

Role: Financial Officer

Dates volunteered: Jul 2013 - Oct 2017

Responsible for all things related to finances, from paying bills and taxes to planning annual budgets, fundraising, grant proposals, and coordinating with the certified public accountant and financial officers of the umbrella organization International Fellowship of Evangelical Students (IFES/InterVarsity). The Student Evangelical Association of Macedonia has existed since 1998 as a network of local student groups committed to evangelism, formación, and mission.

- Mission: Students reaching students in North Macedonia with the gospel of Christ and living as witnessing communities of salt and light in every area of society and culture.
- Vision: The IFES vision is to see students built into communities of disciples, transformed by the gospel and impacting the university, the church, and society for the glory of Christ. https://ifesworld.org/en/region/europe/ > North Macedonia

Organization Name: HBM (CBMC Macedonia)

Role: Team Member

Dates volunteered: Oct 2010 - Jun 2013

"Christian Business Network in Macedonia" (CBMC-Macedonia) ~ marketplace ministry.

https://www.facebook.com/HBM.MKD/

https://www.hbm.mk